{
    "id": "868386f84dff4b10804b5d8aefe7a128",
    "title": "Idioms Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I am sure he will never set the ……………………. on fire.",
            "description": "To set the Thames on fire is to do something remarkable.",
            "answers": [
                "Mississippi",
                "Thames",
                "Danube"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "39662dc4897543cb82a89a9aca8d17e7"
        },
        {
            "question": "The police suspect that he had a …………………….. in the plot.",
            "description": "To have a hand in something is to be involved in it.",
            "answers": [
                "hand",
                "nose",
                "teeth"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "8cdb5eb7eb9c4508aaa8c5d39ac2870b"
        },
        {
            "question": "Please do not take failure to ……………………..",
            "description": "When you take something to heart, you are deeply affected by it. ",
            "answers": [
                "brain",
                "mind",
                "heart"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "a4cfe8f0693f4f3d92c28ebd6d99dcb1"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am afraid you are burning the …………………….. at both ends.",
            "description": "To burn the candle at both ends is to exhaust your energies.",
            "answers": [
                "wick",
                "log",
                "candle"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "f55a06aa6aee4e6db8d91e1518dc93eb"
        },
        {
            "question": "As a writer, Bernard Shaw was head and ………………………….. above his contemporaries.",
            "description": "When you are head and shoulders above others, you are much better than them.",
            "answers": [
                "shoulders",
                "neck",
                "chest"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "62db546eceb74b50b756bfb354871df5"
        },
        {
            "question": "The foolish man made ducks and ……………………… of his wealth.",
            "description": "To make ducks and drakes of one’s wealth is to squander it.",
            "answers": [
                "geese",
                "rats",
                "drakes"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "0045008492214d6a95affb1564e13a51"
        },
        {
            "question": "Although I have known her for a long time, she always gives me the cold …………………..",
            "description": "To give someone the cold shoulder is to show unfriendliness.",
            "answers": [
                "hand",
                "head",
                "shoulder"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "c865745da95949d3b6d57ebd628c425d"
        },
        {
            "question": "He is quite fond of blowing his own ……………………..",
            "description": "To blow one’s own trumpet is to praise oneself.",
            "answers": [
                "whistle",
                "trumpet",
                "flute"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "362be268cc33499fada3440acce2402e"
        },
        {
            "question": "A spirit of unrest is in the ………………………….",
            "description": "\r\nIf something is in the air it is prevalent.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "wind",
                "sky",
                "air"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "fadcf15380cb41b1b646534e6943f3cd"
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t think that you should accept that job. You already have too many ………………………. in the fire.",
            "description": "To have too many irons in the fire is to be engaged in too many activities at the same time.",
            "answers": [
                "logs",
                "irons",
                "knives"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6e8313b2115049d49eb919bf32e17ef3"
        },
        {
            "question": "I have a …………………… to pick with you.",
            "description": "When you have a bone to pick with somebody, you have a reason to quarrel with them.",
            "answers": [
                "bone",
                "screw",
                "nail"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "be4f7a80434d49ccad1a4b0478cf1644"
        },
        {
            "question": "All of his projects ended in …………………..",
            "description": "To end in smoke is to come to nothing.",
            "answers": [
                "smoke",
                "fire",
                "fog"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "af1f2b1559374946b24933e8bfdf7214"
        }
    ]
}